https://www.australiantraveller.com/privacy-policy/

PRIVACY POLICY - Australian Traveller
Toggle navigation
DestinationsACTCanberraNSWSydneyBlue MountainsLord Howe IslandDubboMudgeeOrangeNewcastleNorth CoastByron BayCoffs HarbourHunter ValleyPort MacquariePort StephensOutback NSWBroken HillRiverinaWagga WaggaSnowy MountainsJindabynePerisherThredboSouth CoastJervis BayWollongongSouthern HighlandsBowralNTAlice SpringsArnhem LandDarwinKakaduKatherineRed CentreUluruQLDBrisbaneBundabergFraser IslandHervey BayGold CoastGreat Barrier ReefMoreton IslandOutback QueenslandLongreachRockhamptonSunshine CoastNoosaThe Whitsunday IslandsHamilton IslandTownsvilleTropical North QLDCairnsCape YorkDaintree RainforestPort DouglasSAAdelaideBarossa ValleyEyre PeninsulaKangaroo IslandMcLaren ValeOutback South AustraliaTASLauncestonEast Coast TasmaniaSouth TasmaniaHobartVICMelbourneBallaratBendigoDaylesford Hepburn SpringsGeelongGippslandPhillip IslandGreat Ocean RoadHigh CountryMornington PeninsulaYarra ValleyWAPerthRottnest IslandBroomeCoral Coast & NingalooThe KimberleyMargaret RiverOutback Western AustraliaThe PilbaraExperiencesVirtual TravelAffordable HolidaysAir TravelBeach HolidaysCamping HolidaysCruisingDriving HolidaysEating OutFamily HolidaysFood & WineIsland HolidaysLuxury EscapesOutback HolidaysRomantic GetawaysSki and snowWalking & HikingWeekend BreaksDealsAccommodationAdelaideBrisbaneCanberraDarwinGold CoastHobartMelbournePerthSydneyTop 100 Guides100 Ways to Holiday Here This YearTop 100 reasons to get off the couch100 Greatest Holidays of Australia100 Best Towns in Australia100 Things To Do Before you Die100 Best Views in Australia100 Awesome Places to Hang Out100 Amazing Places You Haven’t Been to Yet100 Things You Can ONLY Do In Australia100 Things To Do In Australia You’ve Never Heard OfWin
Australian Traveller
PRIVACY POLICYPRIVACY POLICY Australian Traveller Media Privacy PolicyAustralian Traveller Media is committed to protecting your privacy. We understand that our customers are concerned about the privacy, confidentiality and security of their personal information. Australian Traveller Media Pty Ltd ACN 113 975 438 (ATM) is bound by the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) as amended by the Privacy Amendment (Private Sector) Amendment Act (2000) (Act). If you are from the European Union, ATM processes information in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). If you are over the age of 16, you provide us with this consent but if you are younger, your parent or guardian will need to provide their consent.What information do we collect from our customers?Any personal information we collect is solely for professional and administrative purposes. The Act defines “Personal Information” to mean “any information or opinion about an identified individual, or an individual who is reasonably identifiable, whether the information or opinion is true or not and whether the information or opinion is recorded in a material form or not”.Personal Information we collect includes our customers’ name, email, shipping and billing address, payment details, company name, phone number, IP address, information about the pages on our website that our customers visit, and information about the device and browser our customers use.Personal Information can also include information about any transactions, both free and paid, that you enter into on the website, and information about you that is available on the internet, such as from Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter and Google, or publicly available information that we acquire from service providers.How do we hold personal information? The personal information that you provide to us may be held in a number of different formats including software programs (located both onsite and offsite, including in the cloud), databases, filing systems and in offsite backup storage. Personal information held by ATM may be stored in email accounts that are accessible through mobile devices.We employ strict security and staff training procedures to protect your personal information from loss, misuse, and unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. However, we cannot ensure the security of any information that you transmit to us over the Internet and you do so at your own risk.Purpose of collecting personal informationWe use this information to provide our customers with products and services, including supporting and processing bookings, risk and fraud screening, authentication, and payments. We also use this information to improve our products and services.We additionally use this information to help customise and improve our customer’s experience when our customers visit our website or apps by presenting our customers with goods and services that are more likely to be of interest to our customersWe use some of the personal information our customers provide us to conduct some level of automated decision-making — for example, we use certain personal information (for example, IP addresses or payment information) to automatically suggest currency types and block certain potentially fraudulent transactions for a short period of time.When do we collect this information?We collect this information when our customers use or access our website or apps to communicate with us or place an order. It is also collected when you join our mailing list, subscribe to our magazines, subscribe to our newsletters or enter into promotions or competitions.Additionally, we partner with third parties who provide us information about our customers, for example, to help us screen out merchants associated with fraud. We note, however, that information provided to those third parties by you is governed by any privacy policy provided by the third party and not by Australian Traveller Media Pty Ltd.Third party distributionWe will only use or disclose and process your personal information:* as permitted by applicable legislation;* for the purpose for which it was collected (as outlined above);* for another related purpose for which you would reasonably expect us to use it; or* for any other purpose with your consent (whether express or implied).The personal information that you provide is recorded on a secure database. It will only be used to send you information from ATM and will not be passed on or sold to any other organisation. In certain circumstances, however, ATM may use or disclose your personal information:* where required or authorised by or under an Australian law (including the Privacy Act) or an order of a court or tribunal;* if reasonably necessary for a legal proceeding or claim;* to any other person authorised and specified by you.We will take reasonable steps to manage and protect your personal information and ensure that any personal information disclosed to a third party is protected by that party in accordance with the Act.We may also use some of the personal information to obtain insights into the needs and interests of our customers. These insights may be shared with third parties but personal information provided to Australian Traveller Media Pty Ltd will be de-identified.Access to personal informationYou may request to see your personal information held by us and request its correction if it is inaccurate.European Union ResidentsIf you are a resident of the European Union, you have several additional rights. These are set out, with a brief explanation below.The right to be forgotten and right of erasure You may ask for any data provided to ATM to be deleted in certain circumstances including when no longer necessary for the purpose it was provided, on request where your consent is withdrawn, when required by law, where it has been unlawfully processed. There are some exceptions, for instance, for the establishment, exercise of defence of legal claims, compliance with applicable law or where processing is necessary for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information.The right of access by an individual In addition to the rights already contained in this Privacy Policy, you may request to see your personal information held by us and obtain information as to the envisaged period of how long personal data will be stored, information as to the source of the data if you are not the source of the data, information as to the existence of automated decision-making including profiling and meaningful information about the logic involved as well as the significance and the envisaged consequences of such processing for you. ATM will be entitled to charge a reasonable fee based on administrative costs for copies of the personal data undergoing processing.The right to restriction of processing You may ask ATM for a restriction of processing in certain circumstances including if you contest the accuracy of the personal data or if the processing is unlawful and you request restriction rather than erasure of the data or if the data is no longer needed for the purpose but may be required to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim or if you have objected to processing pending verification of whether ATM’s legitimate grounds override your interests. In such circumstances, ATM will only process data in accordance with such restrictions or as allowed under the GDPR.The right to data portability In certain circumstances such as when data processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive personal data you have provided to ATM in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format and have the right to transmit that data to another entity if the data processing we carry out is by automated means.The use of cookies and web beacons through our websites and appsInformation may be collected when you access our websites or apps, such as the time and specific page or app you visited. This information is collected through “cookies”. A “cookie” is a small piece of information, or file, that a website or app sends to your computer’s hard drive while you are viewing that website or app for record keeping purposes. Most web browsers are automatically set to accept cookies. If you do not wish to receive any cookies you may set your browser to refuse cookies. However, this will mean you will not be able to take full advantage of our websites or apps.We, and our service providers, use the information collected from cookies for a number of reasons:* for statistical purposes in order to track how many users we have and how often they visit our website or apps;* to provide statistical data, ratings and other information for industry and other public reporting;* to provide you with a more personalised, convenient and interactive experience on our websites or apps;* to track who has viewed an advertisement or clicked-through an advertisement; and* to provide you with a more targeted advertising experience both on and off our websites or apps, allowing us to impose restrictions where appropriate and monitor how effective an advertising campaign has been.We engage various analytic programs to analyse the performance of our websites and apps and to provide us with reports that contain aggregated, de-identified benchmark information that assists us to understand when, and how many times, you have used our websites or apps. The anonymous information assists us in the selection of advertisements for groups of individuals.We may also use Google Analytics features (including Google Remarketing, Google Display Network Impressions Reporting, the Double Click Campaign Manager and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting) on our websites and apps. Google Analytics uses both first party and third party cookies to record standard internet traffic information such as when, and how many times, you have visited our websites or apps. We, and some third parties also use the information to optimise advertising selection for groups of individuals based on demographic information. The cookies allow us and other third parties to evaluate your interactions with advertising services on our websites and apps and serve targeted advertising on those websites and apps and across the Internet. We have enabled Google Analytics for Display Advertising, which allows Google and other third parties to advertise to you on our websites and apps and across the Internet. By using Google Ads Settings (located at https://www.google.com/settings/ads), you can opt out of these features at any time and customise your Google Display Network Ads. Alternatively, you can opt out of a third party’s vendor’s use of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page (located at https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) or specifcially our advertiisng retargettign paltofrm AdRoll here https://www.adrollgroup.com/privacy.Compliance with Our Privacy PolicyWe use the information we collect only in compliance with this Privacy Policy and applicable privacy legislation. Customers who use our services are obligated through our agreements with them to comply with this Privacy Policy.Notifiable Breaches The Privacy Amendment (Notifiable Data Breaches) Act 2017 (Cth) and/or the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) requires us to notify the relevant parties if there is an eligible data breach. This means we will let you know in the way we normally communicate with you, if:* There is unauthorised access to or disclosure of your information; or your information is lost and unauthorised access or disclosure is likely to occur; and* There is a reasonable chance that this could cause you serious harm (which can include physical, physiological, emotional, economic or reputational harm); and* We have been unable to remedy the situation in line with the Act.If we are unable to contact any affected parties individually we will post a notification that an eligible data breach has occurred on our website.In such circumstances we are also required to inform the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner.We will follow our Notifiable Data Breach Procedure in these instances.Changes to our Privacy PolicyAustralian Traveller Media may update this Privacy Policy when necessary. For this reason, you should regularly check our policy to ensure that you are up to date on our policy.How to contact Australian Traveller Media about data privacyYou can access this information at any time or request deletion and removal from our database by contacting us at privacyofficer@AustralianTraveller.com. Alternatively please write to: The Privacy Officer Australian Traveller Media PO Box Broadway NSW 2007 For further information about privacy issues, see the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner’s website at www.oaic.gov.au
SUBSCRIBE NOW For the best travel inspiration delivered straight to your door.$27.95 for 12 months100 Ways to Holiday Here This Year is out now. VIEW SUBSCRIPTION OPTIONS >
Sign up for our newsletterGet the latest travel news, reviews, offers and more, direct to your inbox.
Join Now >
About UsAdvertiseSite MapPrivacyCompetitionsContact© Australian Traveller Media 2020. All rights reserved. ×
For more of the best in travel sign up to our newsletter!
Reload Subscribe Now
